Guillermo R. Rodríguez

Santa Clara, CA 95053 • 919-537-2075 • <u>grromaguera@gmail.com</u> Link to Reel • Link to Website

Writer, Director, Producer & Editor

I have twenty years of experience as a filmmaker and professional editor. I am also Assistant Professor of Communication at Santa Clara University where I teach film production courses that integrate film theory into the filmmaking and post-production process through a Latinx lens.

Areas of expertise include...

VIDEO EDITING	VIDEO PRODUCTION	WRITING
 Avid, Premiere, Final Cut Pro Sound Editing and Mixing Color Correction Graphics and Special Effects 	 National Television Promos Theatrical & Home Video Trailers Mainstream Show Opens Narrative Film & Documentaries 	Website Content

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2022-Now

Assistant Professor, Department of Communication, Santa Clara University

- Duties include teaching production and film studies, undergraduate advising, and serving in departmental and university-wide committees.
- Current courses:
 - Digital Filmmaking (Fall 2022, Winter 2023)
 - Short Fiction Production (Spring 2023)
 - Latinx Cinema (Spring 2023)

2017-2022

Teaching Assistant Professor, Department of English and Comparative Literature, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill

- Duties include teaching pre-production, production and post-production, undergraduate and graduate advising, and serving in departmental and university-wide committees.
- I teach film production and multimedia composition (in the form of documentaries, video essays and audio podcasts) using digital cameras, smartphones, lavaliers and shotgun mics for production, and Adobe Premiere Pro and Audition for post-production.
- Courses designed and taught:
 - Video Games and Narrative Cinema (Fall 2021, Spring 2022)
 - Crafting the Dramatic Film: Theory Meets Practice (Fall 2020, Spring 2021, Fall 2021, Spring 2022)
 - Comics as Literature (Fall 2021)
 - Introduction to Latina/o Studies (Spring 2020)
 - Horror & the Global Gothic: Film, Literature, Theory (Spring 2020, Fall 2020, Spring 2021)
 - Film and Politics (Fall 2019)
 - Horror (Spring 2019, Summer 2019, Fall 2019, Summer 2020, Summer 2021)
 - Film and Culture (Spring 2018, Fall 2018, Spring 2019)
 - English Composition & Rhetoric (Fall 2017, Spring/Summer/Fall 2018, Spring/Summer/Fall 2019, Spring/Summer/Fall 2020, Spring/Summer/Fall 2021, Spring 2022)

2020-2021 Producer and Editor, *Totem Goat* (HD Color 20 minutes), Dir. Jennipher Foster

- Released: February 22, 2022 (France)
- Nominee Best Horror and Winner Best Sound Design, Cannes Short Film Festival 2022
- Winner Best Horror Short Film & Winner Best Score, Madonie Film Festival 2022 in Sicily, Italy
- Official Selection, Hasting Rocks International Film Festival 2022, Hastings, UK
- Winner Best Horror, Winner Best Director Short Film; Honorable Mention Original Score;
 Honorable Mention Sound Design, Florence Film Awards 2022 in Florence, Italy
- Official Selection, Animalis Fabula Film Festival 2022, Austin, TX
- Official Selection, Oregon Screams Horror Film Festival 2022, Portland, OR

Producer, Editor and Writer, Nightcaps of the Living Dead (Podcast – 18 episodes)

Producer, Director and Editor, News-Based Covid-19 Stress Task

Reenactment of an Interview with a Covid-19 Nurse for Carolina Stress Institute research
project "A translational approach to identify biomarkers of Covid19-related social stress in
healthcare workers," funded by a Foundation of Hope for Research and Treatment of Mental
Illness Advanced Grant

2015-2016 Research Assistant, Department of Latin American and Iberian Cultures and the Gender Studies Program, University of Southern California

- Preparing book manuscript Aesthetics, Ethics and Trauma in the Cinema of Pedro Almodóvar by Prof. Julián Gutiérrez-Albilla (Fall 2016)
- Co-designed film production component of graduate course "Adapting Through Don Quixote" for Prof. Sherry Velasco (Spring 2016)
- Co-designed film production component of undergraduate course "Gender Conflicts Across Cultural Contexts" for Prof. Sherry Velasco (Fall 2015)
- 2014-2015 Teaching Assistant, Department of Comparative Literature, University of Southern California
 - Courses Taught:
 - On Location: The Place of Literature in Global Cultures (Spring 2015)
 - Crime Stories: Eastern European Fiction from Crime to Punishment (Fall 2014)
- 2013-2014 Assistant Lecturer, Department of Latin American and Iberian Culture, University of Southern California, Los Angeles
 - Courses Taught:
 - Spanish I (Spring 2014)
 - Spanish II (Fall 2013)
- 2011-2014 Editor, On Air Promo Judge Judy, CBS Television City
 - Utilize production, writing, and editing skills to launch new promotional pieces and proficiently operate programs including Avid Media Composer, FCP, and Adobe Creative Suite (Premiere, After Effects, Photoshop, Illustrator). Thrive under harsh deadlines in pressuredriven environments.
- 2012 Editor, Amanda & Lindsay (HD Color 2 Minutes), Dir. Blass Blas
- 2011 Promo Editor, DirecTV Latin America

Editor, *The Cooking Lady* (Reality TV Series – Cooking Show), Thunder Communications Co-writer, *Killer Ending* and *Deadly Affairs* (TV feature films), Incendo Media

2010 Editor, Born and Bred (Documentary, HD Color 90 minutes), Dir. Justin Frimmer

Released: 2011. Distributor: Warner Bros. Available on Amazon Prime.

Editor, The Prettiest Girl (HD Color 10 minutes), Film Independent Director's Lab,

• Mentor: Catherine Hardwicke, Dir. Sasha Isaac-Young

Sizzle Reels Editor, Secret Handshake Entertainment

2009 Director and Editor, 12 Volt CarAoke commercial "Car Dance Mob," Sabatino Day

Editor, Where The Road Meets The Sun (35mm Color 90 Minutes), Dir. Mun Chee Yong

- Released: 2011. Distributor: Maya Entertainment. Available on Amazon Prime.
- Special Jury Award for Best Acting Ensemble & Outstanding Cinematography, Los Angeles Asian Pacific Film Festival 2011
- Official Selection, S\u00e30 Paulo International Film Festival 2011

Additional Editor, Stasis (35mm Color 30 Minutes), Dir. Christian Swegal

2008 Producer and Editor, Sweet Thing (16mm Color 80 Minutes), Dir. Joe Lia

- Dramatic Competition, Santa Barbara International Film Festival 2009
- Official Selection, Seattle International Film Festival 2008
- Official Selection, Boston International Film Festival 2008

Editor, U-Direct NYC, *Diapers.com* (30s Commercials *The Ad Store*)

Editor, Gangland Season 2 (The History Channel), Towers Productions

2007 Promo Editor, Affiliate Promotional Services, NBC Universal

• Heroes, Chuck, Life, ER, Law & Order, Bionic Woman, 30 Rock, The Office (TV Spots)

Writer, Director, Producer and Editor, *The Shadows* (HD Color 80 Minutes)

- Release: October 28, 2008 (Water Bearer Films). Available on Amazon Prime.
- Official Selection (Dramatic Competition), Outfest 2007: Los Angeles LGBTQ Film Festival
- Official Selection, Reeling 26: The Chicago Lesbian & Gay Intl. Film Festival
- Official Selection, Melbourne Queer Film Festival 2008
- Official Selection, Film Out San Diego Film Festival 2008

Editor, Bait Car (Court TV), New Box Media

Editor, Peggy Rajski Productions

- Somewhere Over the Rainbow (Documentary Short, HD Color 20 Minutes)
- Alone No Love (Documentary Short, HD Color 30 Minutes)
- Trevor (I-Tunes Spot, 35mm Color 3 Minutes)

Promo Editor, America's Got Talent Season 3 (NBC), Freemantle Media

2006 Trailer Editor, All The Days Before Tomorrow (35mm Color 100 Mins), Kangoo Films

Trailer Editor, *Shamelove* (16mm Color 79 Mins), Mentone Pictures

Assistant Editor, Alexis Arquette: She's My Brother (Documentary), A&E/Channel 4

Assistant Editor, Freemantle Media

 Property Ladder Season 2, American Idol Best & Worst DVD, Janice Dickinson Modeling Agency, Mediums at Large

2005 Writer, *The Accident* (16mm 13 Minutes), Dir. David Person

- Aired on The Independent Film Channel, June 2005
- Official Selection, 2005 First Look Film Festival, Director's Guild of America

Assistant Editor, Freemantle Media

• Property Ladder Season 1, How Clean is Your House, Love on the Rocks

Assistant Editor, Survivor: Palau (CBS), Mark Burnett Productions

2004 Writer and Director, *Playing* (35mm 21 Minutes), MFA Thesis

- The Caucus for TV Writers, Producers & Directors Outstanding Student Filmmaker Award
- First look Film Festival at the Director's Guild of America
- Riverside Multicultural Youth Film Festival
- Lake Arrowhead Film Festival

Production Designer, 9:30 (35mm Color 12 Minutes), Dir. Mun Chee Yong

Assistant Editor, Survivor: Vanauatu (CBS), Mark Burnett Productions

Assistant Editor, Expeditions to the Edge (National Geographic), GRB Entertainment

2003-2004 Teaching Assistant, School of Cinematic Arts, University of Southern California

As lead teaching assistant of the advanced film production workshop course at USC's School of Cinematic Arts, I oversaw the production process of all undergraduate 16mm thesis projects over the course of two years, including running its post-production on Avid Media Composer and Pro Tools.

2003 Writer, Cinematographer and Director, *The Mirror Maker* (16mm Color 12 Minutes)

Co-Editor, Manuel (35mm Color 17 Minutes), Dir. Gabriel J. Serrano

Editor, Stone (35mm Color 12 Minutes), Dir. Pyongson Yim

Co-Editor, 18 Money (16mm Color 10 Minutes), Dir. Eriko Ueno

2002 Writer, Director and Editor, Alice Awakens (16mm Color 5 Minutes)

Writer, Director and Editor, Four Walls (DV 13 Minutes)

Director and Editor, The Shield (DV 12 Minutes)

2001 Writer, Director and Sound Designer, Quiet in the Hallway (16mm B&W 5 Minutes)

Cinematographer and Editor, Honor Among Thieves (16mm B&W 5 Minutes), Dir. Mark Shoeman

Grip, In The Land of Milk & Money (35mm Color 90 Minutes), Dir. Susan Emshwiller

Writer, Director, Cinematographer and Editor, *Inversion* (DV 7 Minutes)

Writer, Director, Cinematographer and Editor, *The Heat in Shadows* (DV 5 Minutes)

Writer, Director, Cinematographer and Editor, *Just α Little Piece* (DV 6 Minutes)

Writer, Director, Cinematographer and Editor, Strings at Midnight (DV 8 Minutes)

Writer, Director, Cinematographer and Editor, *The Suicide Watch* (DV 3 Minutes)

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Comparative Media and Culture, University of Southern California, 2017 M.A. Comparative Media and Culture, University of Southern California, 2015 M.F.A. Cinema-Television Production, University of Southern California, 2004 A.B. Comparative Literature and Latin American Studies, Princeton University, 1999

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES

Avid Media Composer; Adobe Premiere; Final Cut; Microsoft Office Suite; Adobe Creative Suite; Final Draft; Movie Magic Budgeting and Scheduling; Mac OSX, PC.